Knowledge distillation allows large and
complex models to transfer their learned
knowledge to [music] smaller and more
efficient models. In simple
classification, we feed an image to a
large pre-trained model such as ResNet
or VGG. We get some probability
distribution for the class this image
belongs to. [music] Then we use the
labels from our data set for guiding the
model to predict the correct class. We
can do it with cross entropy loss. But
for knowledge distillation, we take a
better and well-trained model and get
its [music] predictions for the same
image. These predictions are called soft
labels because they provide more
accurate labels for the given image
because it has some dark knowledge. For
this example, you can see the model is
quite confident that this image is a
cat. But you know a cat is more similar
to a dog compared to a snake. So we have
a higher probability for dog [music]
compared to snake. This additional
information is not present in the actual
label which is just cat. [music] Now we
train the smaller model to match these
soft labels from the larger model using
KL divergence which guides the model to
learn better.